Guide to the James Thomas Flexner Papers 1920s - 1990s MS 220
New-York Historical Society
- Series XX. Miscellaneous correspondence and subject files, circa 1933-1971
  - For Writing Anthology [folder], before 1998? (Offsite-box 53)
    Scope and Contents
    Material perhaps intended for Random Harvest (1998), a collection of Flexner's essays, reviews, and other writings.
  - G, 1955-1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - H, 1959-1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - Hicus [card file], undated (Offsite-box 1)
  - I, 1959-1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - L – Correspondence [folder], 1945-1952 (Offsite-box 18)
  - Library of Congress – Grant in aid [folder], undated (Offsite-box 19)
  - Little Brown, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 52)
  - Lowell Institute – Correspondence [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Lowell Lectures, undated (Offsite-box 52)
  - M, 1953-1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - Magazine articles – General – Correspondence, drafts [folder], 1943 (Offsite-box 18)
  - Magazine of Art – Correspondence [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - McCullough, undated (Offsite-box 52)
  - McKeogh & Boyd – Correspondence [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Metropolitan Museum, to 1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - Monochromatic Drawing [card file], undated (Offsite-box 1)
  - N, 1953-1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - National Book Award, 1969 (Offsite-box 52)
  - [New-York Historical Society] Laid Aside – Add to File at Hist. Soc., Feb. 1993 – Correspondence, clippings, drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - [New-York Historical Society] For Historical Society – seen 5/8/97 (contains drafts), undated (Offsite-box 30)
  - [New-York Historical Society] Early drafts and fragments preserved in bookcase at the New-York Historical Society – Gathered together Feb. 1981 [folder], undated (Offsite-box 32)
  - New York Times – Correspondence [folder], 1953-1960 (Offsite-box 19)
  - Notebook [folder], before 1933 (Offsite-box 18)
  - Notebook – Clippings, notes, drafts [folder], 1933-1936 (Offsite-box 18)
  - Nudes & Prudes, undated (Offsite-box 52)
  - O, 1953-1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - Old versions – Drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Opus II – Discarded Sections – Drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Opus II – Rough Drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Opus II – Notes, drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 19)
  - P – Correspondence [folder], 1945-1948 (Offsite-box 19)
  - P, to 1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - P.E.N.—Post-President, undated (Offsite-box 52)
  - S, 1955-1971 (Offsite-box 52)
  - Short Stories – The True History of John Goodman; Riot Call; The Commissioner's Ghost; Return – drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 19)
  - Skira (publisher) – Correspondence, notes [folder], undated (Offsite-box 19)
  - Mari Stevenson – Correspondence [folder], undated (Offsite-box 19)
  - T, 1953-1972 (Offsite-box 52)
  - United States Information Agency – correspondence [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - U.S. Productions – Correspondence, drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - U.V. [University of Virginia] – Correspondence [folder], 1945-1952 (Offsite-box 18)
  - Unpublished Materials – Drafts, copies [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Viking Press – Correspondence [folder], 1942-1944 (Offsite-box 18)
  - Viking Press – Financial – Doctor & Painters – also Heinemann [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - W, 1953-1972 (Offsite-box 52)
  - War articles – Drafts [folder], undated (Offsite-box 19)
  - Williamsburg – Architectural Material [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Williamsburg – Correspondence [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Williamsburg – Financial [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Williamsburg – Reports [folder], undated (Offsite-box 18)
  - Williamsburg – Information [folder], undated (Offsite-box 27)
  - [Williamsburg] Columbia Lecture – Williamsburg Project – Read by JTF 1992, undated (Offsite-box 41)